(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
燃え上がれ 燃え上がれ 燃え上がれ ガンダム
Burn! Burn! Burn! Gundam!
君よ 走れ
You, run!
まだ怒りに燃える 闘志があるなら
If you still have fighting spirit burning with rage,
巨大な敵を 打てよ 打てよ 打てよ
Strike the giant enemy! Strike! Strike! Strike!
正義の怒りを ぶつけろ ガンダム
Unleash your righteous rage, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam!
ガンダム
Gundam!
立ち上がれ 立ち上がれ 立ち上がれ ガンダム
Stand up! Stand up! Stand up! Gundam!
君よ 叫べ
You, shout!
まだ絶望に沈む 悲しみあるなら
If you still have sadness sinking in despair,
恐怖をはらって ゆけよ ゆけよ ゆけよ
Shake off the fear! Go! Go! Go!
渦巻く命を 燃やせ ガンダム
Burn your swirling life, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam!
ガンダム
Gundam!
皆さん！
Everyone!
周防パトラ生誕祭にお越しいただいて
Thank you so much for coming to
どうもありがとうございます！
Suou Patra's Birthday Party!
パトラ、行きまーす！
Patra, moving out!
蘇る 蘇る 蘇る ガンダム
Rise again! Rise again! Rise again! Gundam!
君よ 掴め
You, grab hold!
まだ愛に震える 心があるなら
If you still have a heart trembling with love,
平和を求めて 飛べよ 飛べよ 飛べよ
Seeking peace, fly! Fly! Fly!
銀河へ向かって 飛べよ ガンダム
Fly towards the galaxy, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム
Mobile Suit Gundam!
ガンダム
Gundam!
適性の記憶
Memories of compatibility.
これは、先帝たちの...
This is, from the former emperors...
今、受け継ごう
Now, let us inherit it.
歴代のパトラの力と記憶を
The power and memories of all previous Patras.
はい！ということで最終行程
Yes! And so, for the final stage,
周防パトラですわー！
I am Suou Patra!
今回も豪華ステージ、そして新衣装！
A gorgeous stage again, and a new costume!
さらに巨大カニカマもいるよーということで
And we even have a giant crab stick here!
お待たせ！
Thanks for waiting!
改めまして、こんばんはわー！
Once again, good evening-wa!
そう、パトラ生誕祭、お越しいただきありがとうございます！
That's right, thank you for coming to Patra's Birthday Party!
はい。見てください。まずは新衣装、
Yes. Please look. First of all, the new outfit,
気になってる方も多いと思うんですけど...
I think many of you are curious about it...
あ、椅子の方が気になりますが、
Oh, the chair is more noticeable, but...
これロマサガ2風です。はい。
this is in the style of Romancing SaGa 2. Yes.
はい。じゃあ、下からね。
Alright. Starting from the bottom.
なんと、はい、靴！
Wow, look, shoes!
ちゃんと今回も新衣装なんですけど、
This is part of the new outfit too, but...
あの、ヒールがあります！
um, there are heels!
間違えた、ヒールがあります！
My mistake, I meant heels!
そして、このベルトも可愛いでしょ？
And this belt is cute too, right?
で、今回は鉄壁のスカートになっております！
And this time, it's an ironclad skirt!
結構ね動いても、
Even if I move around a lot,
はい、鉄壁で頑丈になっております！
yes, it's ironclad and sturdy!
それから、おへそ！
And then, my belly button!
見て見て見て、セクシーでしょ？
Look, look, look, it's sexy, right?
そしてベルトもね、かっちりなっております！
And the belt too, is fastened tightly!
白衣装の時よりちょっと抑えられてるんで、
It's a bit more restrained than when I was in my white outfit,
揺れが、あのちょっと足りないかもしれないんですけど、
so the "jiggle" might be a bit lacking, but...
今回もボインボインでお送りいたします！
I'll be bringing you boing-boing again today!
そしてそして、じゃん！ポニーテール！
And next, ta-da! A ponytail!
新髪型になっております。
It's a new hairstyle.
ハートのね、アクセサリーが揺れて
The heart accessory swaying is...
可愛いでしょ、これも。
...cute too, isn't it?
ほれほれほれ。
Look, look, look.
という感じで、とっても可愛い新衣装になりました！
And so, it's become a very cute new outfit!
さらに、みんなが気になってると思うんですけど、
Furthermore, I think everyone's curious about this, but...
ぱー！なんと脱げまーす！
Ta-da! I can take it off!
え、これYouTube的に大丈夫かな？
Um, is this okay for YouTube?
大丈夫かな？
Is it okay?
見て見て見て見て。こうね、ハートのくり抜きがあるんですよ。
Look, look, look, look. There's a heart cutout right here.
いや、背中の筋が
Wow, the lines on my back are...
またセクシーですね。
...sexy too.
あ、そうそう、今回もちゃんと、
Oh, right, this time too, yes...
はい、脇が丸見えになっております。
...my armpits are fully visible.
たくさんたくさん、スクショ待ってます！
I'm waiting for lots and lots of screenshots!
はい。ということで、ハッシュタグ「#周防パトラ生誕祭」でよろしくお願いします。
Yes. So, please use the hashtag #周防パトラ生誕祭.
感想とかね、あのコメント待ってるよ。
I'm waiting for your thoughts and comments.
お、可愛いコメントいっぱいありがとう！
Oh, thanks for all the cute comments!
はーい。いっぱい撮ってくださいね。
Yes. Please take lots of photos.
ふっふっふっ。
Huff, huff, huff.
あの、なんかセクシーな格好がどうやればいいのかわからないんだけど、
I'm not sure how to pose sexily, but...
皆さんのスクショテクにお任せします！
I'll leave it to your screenshotting skills!
じゃあ、早速次の曲行きたいと思います！
Now, let's head straight to the next song!
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? You troubled child
UNLUCKY? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Even those who aren't human
BE HAPPY! 弛まず目指せよ
Be happy! Aim endlessly
アンデッド! 生きているんだし
Undead! You're alive, aren't you?
目を逸らした過去も
Even the past you turned away from
退屈な未来も
And the boring future
カウンセリング やれやれ
Counseling, oh well
古今東西 ピースピース
Peace, peace from here to there
UNHAPPY? UNLUCKY? BE HAPPY!
アンデッド! アンデ、アンデッドッドッド
Undead! Undead, undead, undead!
ねえ、ねえ、ねえ、ねえ なんだかどうして
Hey, hey, hey, hey, why...
戦ってるような そんな気がするの
...does it feel like I'm fighting something?
触れられない 触れたくない 過去の自分 自分 自分 自分
Can't touch, don't want to touch the past self, self, self, self
もう死んで
Already dead
透明な幽霊と対峙して
Confronting transparent ghosts
幼い頃の 痛い記憶 悔やんでも
Painful memories of childhood, even if I regret them...
もういないのに
...though they're gone now
ねえ？ そっちのがいっそ 皮肉だね
Huh? That's actually more ironic
今の自分を見透かされてる？
Is the current self being seen through?
ナンセンス ナンセンス もう死んで もう死んで
Nonsense, nonsense, already dead, already dead
言えず 弱コンプレックス
Unspoken, weak complex
取り憑かれてるみたい
As if possessed
巻きついたまま
Coiled around me
まだ離れない
Still won't let go
ありし日の自分
My former self
アンデッド!
Undead!
心臓のない オールマイティ マインドステート
Heartless, almighty mind state
生きてることとは 変わり続けることだろ
Living means continuing to change, right?
不孝に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't settle for being unhappy and be satisfied
幸せになろうとしないなんて 虚談
Not trying to be happy is a lie
この世 この世は 奇々怪々ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre fantasy
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will an ogre appear next, or a snake?
当てて 当ててよ 始まる物語
Guess, guess it, the story that's starting
人と化け物が 交わしたディビディビ
Humans and monsters exchanged a 'divi-divi'
But you can't change the past
But you can laugh on the future
なんだかどうして 未来に難題の
For some reason, why does the future have such difficult problems?
ドブさらい的 予兆な気がして
Like a premonition of scavenging through a gutter?
猛スピード生きてる 既視感とテンプレ省力
Living at high speed, deja vu and cutting corners
素敵だ出来事の気配もない
No sign of any wonderful events either
残念 済んだ経験の 因果経過 加算された神話と
Too bad, the causal process of past experiences and added myths
退屈な進化よ 刺激が欲しいんだ 億劫になっちゃった
Boring evolution, I want stimulation, it's become a hassle
断定 整っていくガイダンス
Conclusion, guidance is falling into place
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance
突き刺されていくみたい
As if being pierced
透き通る指定
Transparent designation
あでも これも どれも 同じ
Ah, but this, that, everything is the same
アッチカッチ アッチカッチ
Atchi-kotchi, atchi-kotchi
Are you ready?
信じられない オールマイティー マイナスの連鎖
Unbelievable, almighty, a chain of negatives
いつの世も 過去も未来も 今にあるんだ
In any age, the past and future are in the now
生きていることを 愚直に歌うよ 目指せハッピーエンド
I'll sing truthfully about being alive toward a happy ending
Are you ready?
信じられない お前に言ってるんだ
Unbelievable, I'm talking to you
幸せを究めてしまわない ひとであれ
Be a person who never stops seeking happiness
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ
If you just get used to suffering and endure it
死んでるも同然 屍のアゲた
You're as good as dead, the shout of a corpse
悩み事なんてないさ そんな奴もいないさ
There are no worries, no one is like that
止まらず目指せよ 生きているんだろ
Don't stop, aim high, you're alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Wallowing in misery or becoming happy
全部全部お前だ ここに存在さ 咲かせ新天地
It's all up to you, your existence is here, make the new world bloom
P-P-P-Patra
パ！ エクスタシー！ キャプテンザパ！
Pa! Ecstasy! Captain the Pa!
パ！ エクスタシー！ ラブフォーザフューチャー！
Pa! Ecstasy! Love for the future!
人並み外れた いつも例えがたい
Extraordinary and always hard to describe
生き抜くこの化物ばかりのモノ語り
Surviving this story full of nothing but monsters
ちゃっかりしっかり 誕生日グッズのお知らせだよ
Casually but firmly, here's an announcement for birthday goods!
なんと パトラのでっかいマウスパッドや バスタオル
We have Patra's giant mousepad and a bath towel!
そして とっても可愛いアクリルスタンド A4サイズのファイル
And a very cute acrylic stand and A4 size files.
いろんなグッズがある誕生日グッズが登場だよ
A variety of birthday goods are now available!
受注生産なので 売り切れの心配なし
They're made-to-order, so no need to worry about sell-outs.
8月30日までの受付です
Orders are accepted until August 30th.
よろしくお願いします
Please check them out!
FINAL FANTASY V ビッグブリッヂの死闘
FINAL FANTASY V: Battle on the Big Bridge
UNDERTALE Megalovania
ロマンシング サ・ガ2 七英雄バトル
Romancing SaGa 2: Seven Heroes Battle
ロマンシング サ・ガ2 / 七英雄バトル
Romancing SaGa 2 / Seven Heroes Battle
アーマード・コア4 / Panther
Armored Core 4 / Panther
仮面ライダー サモンライド! / Break The World
Kamen Rider SummonRide! / Break The World
放たれた矢が的へ
Like an arrow released heading for the target,
向かうように
I'll keep moving forward.
自らの
I'll let...
気持ちも
...my own feelings...
向かわせ行く
...head forward too.
理由などなく
With no reason,
そこに宿命あるだけ
there is only destiny there.
ただ進む
Just moving forward,
仲間とともにゆく
together with my comrades.
気持ちは一つ
Our feelings are one;
水面に写る君は
you, reflected on the water's surface,
遠くライドゲート
are staring at the distant...
見つめてる
...Ride Gate.
Light and dark 見つめている
Staring at the light and dark
果てなく続く狂ったWorld 突き進む
Pushing through the endless, crazy world
強い意志で限界を打ち破って
Breaking through the limits with a strong will
Summon Ride!
時は満ちて
The time is ripe
Summon Ride! 意志を宿し
Summon Ride! Harboring the will
願いを一つに集め
Gathering our wishes into one
全てを越えて突き抜けろ
Cross over everything and break through
Summon Ride! 空を戦う
Summon Ride! Fighting in the sky
Summon Ride! 此処に舞い
Summon Ride! Dance here
約束の地へ駆け抜けろ
Run through to the promised land
Summon Ride! 時を越えて
Summon Ride! Across time
Summon Ride! 祈り届け
Summon Ride! May our prayers reach
想いを絆に変えて
Changing our feelings into bonds
一点突破突き抜けろ
Break through at a single point
Summon Ride! 次元を越え
Summon Ride! Across dimensions
Summon Ride! 全ては今
Summon Ride! Everything is now
約束の地へ駆け抜けろ
Run through to the promised land
はい！ということで、聴いてくれてありがとうございました！
Yes! So, thank you for listening!
今、何をやってるかと言うと、とってもこの後可愛いゲストが来るので
Right now, what I'm doing is... because some very cute guests are coming next,
フェロモンを出し捲っていました。はぁ...なんかドキドキするな。
I was letting out a lot of pheromones. Hah... I'm getting nervous.
それでは、呼びたいと思います！
Well then, I'd like to call them!
本日のスペシャルゲスト、おいで～！
Today's special guests, come on out~!
おっはよー！
Good morning!
バウバウ！
Bau bau!
パトラ様ー！
Patra-sama!
ハッピーバースデー！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！バウバウ！にゃ、フワモコちゃんの二人に来てもらいました！
Thank you! Bau bau! Meow, I've invited Fuwamoco!
じゃ、自己紹介お願いします。
Well, please introduce yourselves.
はい！チワワじゃないよ、フワワだよ！
Yes! Not a chihuahua, I'm Fuwawa!
フワワじゃないよ、モココだよ！
Not Fuwawa, I'm Mococo!
Hololive English -Advent- の魔界の番犬シスターズ！
The demon guard dog sisters from Hololive English -Advent-!
二人合わせて、フワモコです！バウバウ！
Together, we are Fuwamoco! Bau bau!
はは！バウバウ様、はは！ありがたいです。
Haha! Bau bau-sama, haha! I'm grateful.
いや、フワモコちゃんはパトラがね、ASMRの音をね、プロデュースして
You know, for Fuwamoco, Patra produced their ASMR sounds,
ね、その時濃厚な時間を過ごさせていただいたんだよね。
and we had a very intense time together then, didn't we?
楽しかった！楽しかった！
It was fun! It was fun!
二人のASMRボイス販売中なので、よろしくお願いします！
Their ASMR voices are currently on sale, so check them out!
ありがとうございます！ちょっと恥ずかしい...ちょっと恥ずかしい...
Thank you very much! It's a bit embarrassing... a bit embarrassing...
でも今日はパトラの誕生日だから、何か二人からご褒美がもらえるって聞いたんだけど？
But today is Patra's birthday, so I heard I'd get a reward?
パトラ様のご褒美？
A reward for Patra-sama?
うん。フワモコは聞いてないです！
Yeah. Fuwamoco hasn't heard about this!
そんなそんな...ほら、せっかくの誕生日だしね。
Oh come on... hey, it's a special birthday.
いや、ご褒美どうしようか？モココちゃん？
Well, what should the reward be? Mococo-chan?
ハフハグ...
Sniff, hug...
ハグちゃん...ハフハフ...
Hagu-chan... sniff sniff...
はい、もうどこでも触ってください、ありがとうございます。
Okay, you can touch me anywhere, thank you very much.
角外す。じゃ、せーの！
Taking off my horns. Okay, one-two!
ハッピーバースデー！ハッピーバウバウ！
Happy Birthday! Happy Bau Bau!
幸せ...フワワの方がなんかムニムニして...
So happy... Fuwawa feels more squishy...
あ、ちょっと待って待って...モココちゃん...
Ah, wait wait... Mococo-chan...
モココちゃん、妹なんだから、は～可愛い可愛い...
Mococo-chan is the younger sister, so... ah~ so cute...
可愛い...プルプルプル...頑張ってる可愛い...
Cute... squish squish... trying hard, so cute...
ご褒美だ。今日はね、三人でまたね、歌が歌えると！
It's a reward. Today, the three of us get to sing again!
イヤー！やった～！
Yay! Yay~!
あ、じゃちょっとパトラ露出が激しいので着ますね。ホイ！
Ah, Patra's outfit is a bit too revealing, so I'll change. Swish!
ありがとう！じゃ、早速行きますよ！ホイ！
Thank you! Well, let's get right to it! Hoi!
それでは聴いてください、さくらんぼキッズ！
Then please listen to Sakuranbo Kids!
ぴっ！あれれ、おかしなこのドキドキは
Pii! Oh my, how strange this heartbeat is...
君の腕の中で溢れ出す
Overflowing in your arms...
ポロリ零れた涙さくらんぼ
Cherries, tears that spilled out...
もっとギュっとしていてね
Keep me held tight...
好き好き好き好き
Love love love love
まだまだかな君のハート
Is your heart still not ready?
ちょっと酸っぱい？本当？
A bit sour? Really?
おやおやおや待ちきれない
Oh my, oh my, I can't wait...
このままじゃ...ね、待って！
If it stays like this... Hey, wait!
澄まして顔で決めて...ね、待って！
Decide with a cool face... Hey, wait!
そっぽ向くふりはやだよ
I hate pretending to look away.
なにげなく ふわっと
Casually, lightly,
手を取り回して 瞳近づく
taking hands, spinning, eyes getting closer.
ホントはね... ずっと好きだったの 内緒だよ
Actually... I've always loved you. It's a secret.
イェーイ！
Yay!
あーれれ 小さな胸が震えてる
Oh? My small chest is trembling.
抱きしめられたら 壊れちゃうよ
If you hug me, I might break.
夢で見ていたのより 切ないね
It's more painful than what I saw in my dreams.
だからもっと ギュッとしてね
So please, hold me tighter.
ポロリ はじけたから 涙あふれちゃう
Because it popped, tears overflow.
大人になるための 痛みかな
Is this the pain of growing up?
君に触れられた頬 染まってく
The cheek you touched is turning red.
キスはちょっとだけ待ってね
Wait just a little bit for a kiss.
好き好き好き 好き好き好き 好き好き好き
Love, love, love... Love, love, love...
やだやだ やだよ～ 初心は嫌だ
No way, no way... I don't want to be a beginner.
もっとギュッとしていて
Hold me tighter.
はなはなはなはな 私もまだ
Hana hana hana hana... I'm still...
根性もだもん
still have guts!
君の余裕がグサッと
Your composure stabs me,
胸の奥に刺さるよ
piercing deep into my heart.
この私 スパッと 忘れさせてね
Let me forget this... cleanly,
優しいキスで
with a gentle kiss.
なんだかね... キュンとしちゃうの
Somehow... my heart skips a beat.
内緒だよ
It's a secret.
イェーイ！
Yay!
あーれれ 唇があふれてる
Oh? Lips are tingling.
君のまつげが瞳に映る
Your eyelashes reflect in my eyes.
鼓動波打つ速さ 急上昇
The speed of my heartbeat surges.
だけどちょっと かなり幸せ
But I'm quite happy.
小鳥たちも止まる 瞬間に
In the moment even birds stop,
壊れそうな心 溶けだす
my heart that seems about to break melts.
赤くはじけた私 さくらんぼ
Popped red, I am a cherry.
君とずっと つながっていたい
I want to stay connected with you forever.
あぁ 神様 この唇は
Ah, God, these lips...
彼と誓うために 生まれてきたのですね
were born to make a vow with him, weren't they?
うー、っぴー！
Woo-pee!
すまし顔で決めて
Decide with a serious face,
そっぽ向くふりはやだよ
I hate pretending to look away.
なにげなく ふわっと
Casually, lightly,
手を取り回して 瞳近づく
taking hands, spinning, eyes getting closer.
だってね こんなの初めてなの
Because, you see, this is the first time.
内緒だよ
It's a secret.
いっせーのーで！
One, two...!
あーれれ おかしなこのドキドキは
Oh? This strange pounding heartbeat...
君の腕の中で あふれだす
overflows in your arms.
ポロリ こぼれた涙 さくらんぼ
Tears that spilled, cherry.
もっとギュッと ずっとそばにいて
Hold me tighter, stay by my side forever.
あーれれ 世界がくるり回りだす
Oh? The world starts spinning around.
ふわふわ夢心地 風まかせ
Fluffy dreamlike feeling, at the mercy of the wind.
ずっと待ってた恋は止まらない
The love I've been waiting for won't stop.
だからずっと 離さないで
So please, never let go.
好き好き好き 好き好き好き...
Love, love, love... Love, love, love...
みんなー！周防パトラ生誕祭盛り上げてくれてどうもありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you so much for livening up Suou Patra's birthday festival!
まだまだ歌っちゃうから盛り上げよろしくお願いします！
I'm going to keep singing, so please keep the excitement going!
偉大なる悪魔は実は大天使パトラちゃん様なのだー！
The great demon is actually Archangel Patra-chan-sama!
ピピピピ大魔王イチゴ 買って褒めて甘やかしてよ
Pi-pi-pi-pi Great Demon King Ichigo. Buy, praise, and pamper me.
転んでしおしお泣いたって 戦わないモンスターに負けないで
Even if I fall and cry salty tears, don't lose to monsters that don't fight.
君の運命は自分で切り開け
Carve out your own destiny.
馬鹿って言うほうが馬鹿
The one who calls others stupid is the stupid one.
超セクシーでキュートで断然サイコパスが
Super sexy, cute, and definitely psychopathic,
日本レベル文化的な最低限のボン・ボヤージュ
Japan-level cultural minimum bon voyage.
It's my life!
ムニムニムニムニほっぺムニュ
Muni-muni-muni-muni cheek squeeze.
様々この世に可愛いの いつから悪魔と錯覚していた？
Various cute things in this world. Since when did you have the illusion that I was a demon?
そうだそうだ 僕は大天使のような女の子
That's right, that's right, I'm a girl like an archangel.
右に回れば太陽じゃない 地球が逆回転しちゃうじゃない
Turning right isn't the sun. The Earth might rotate in reverse, wouldn't it?
いいぜいいぜ いつも全部が いつも自分が主人公
It's fine, it's fine, everything is always... I'm always the protagonist.
あー なんか疲れちゃった 時代が追いつくまで待たなきゃ
Ah, I'm kind of tired. Gotta wait until the era catches up.
今日も誕生日！
Today is also my birthday!
ちょっと待って よそ見してるのよ
Wait a minute, you're looking away.
こんなに大好きなのにどういうこと？
I love you this much, so what's the deal?
1000! 1000! 1000! セクシーコメディ
1000! 1000! 1000! Sexy comedy!
全心宇宙です！
It's a whole-hearted universe!
今何だだち 今こそ一致団結
Now, pals! Now is the time for unity!
パトラちゃん様に愛を込めて
With love for Patra-chan-sama!
バッキュン！
Bakkyun!
生きてえらまい 今一期一会
Living is great! This is a once-in-a-lifetime encounter.
満足10回なら 書きだそう どーれで
If you're 10 times satisfied, let's write it down.
全開！ 抱いた 楽しい方でいいでしょ
Full throttle! Just go with the fun side!
いいでしょ！
Is that okay?
生きてえらまい 生きちゃおうぜ
Living is great! Let's just live!
勝手にはじめて 甘やかしちゃおう
Start on your own and let's pamper you.
転んで 自信をなくさないで
Don't lose your confidence when you fall.
戦おうぜ
Let's fight!
モンスターに負けないで
Don't lose to the monsters.
自分の運命は
Your own destiny...
自分で切り拓け
...carve it out yourself!
馬鹿言うほうが馬鹿
The one who says "stupid" is the stupid one!
セクシーでキュートで
Sexy and cute...
サイテー最高ぶりっ子
...the worst and best "burikko"!
健康的で文化的な 最低限度のボインボイン
Healthy and cultural minimum "boin-boin"!
It's My Life
むにむにむにむにハピみゅー
Muni muni muni muni Hapi-myu!
みんな、コメントで応援どうもありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for the support in the comments!
見えてるよー！
I can see you!
おっ、パトラちゃん可愛いって打ってる？
Oh, are you typing that Patra-chan is cute?
ちょ、そこの君！サボってんじゃーないよ！
Hey, you there! Don't slack off!
画面の向こう、見えてるぞー！
I can see you on the other side of the screen!
さあさあ、たくさんコメント打っていいー？
Come on, can you type lots of comments?
笑いあげても気にすんな
Don't mind even if I laugh.
そのまま終わるより素晴らしいと
It's more wonderful than ending just like that...
誇り
...with pride.
お別れの約束を忘れんな
Don't forget the promise of parting.
格好悪く生きろ
Live un-coolly.
傷ついた思い出に
To the hurt memories...
負けない気分になり
...feel like not losing!
みんな、盛り上げてくれてどうもありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for livening things up!
この後は一緒に「パトラちゃん様」と言ってください！
After this, please say "Patra-chan-sama" with me!
せーの！
Ready, go!
パトラちゃん様！
Patra-chan-sama!
どうもありがとう！
Thank you so much!
生きてえらまい 今一期一会
Living is great! This is a once-in-a-lifetime encounter.
満足10回なら 書きだそう どーれで
If you're 10 times satisfied, let's write it down.
全開！ 抱いた 楽しい方でいいでしょ
Full throttle! Just go with the fun side!
いいでしょ！
Is that okay?
生きてえらまい 生きちゃおうぜ
Living is great! Let's just live!
勝手にはじめて 甘やかしちゃおう
Start on your own and let's pamper you.
転んで 自信をなくさないで
Don't lose your confidence when you fall.
戦おうぜ
Let's fight!
モンスターに負けないで
Don't lose to the monsters.
自分の運命は
Your own destiny...
自分で切り拓け
...carve it out yourself!
馬鹿言うほうが馬鹿
The one who says "stupid" is the stupid one!
セクシーでキュートで
Sexy and cute...
サイテー最高ぶりっ子
...the worst and best "burikko"!
健康的で文化的な 最低限度のボインボイン
Healthy and cultural minimum "boin-boin"!
It's My Life
むにむにむにむにハピみゅー
Muni muni muni muni Hapi-myu!
はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
もう一回！
One more time!
はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
移動してるよ！ちょっと待ってね！
I'm moving! Wait just a bit!
Quiet Night C.E.73
はい！皆さん、ラクス・クラインです！
Yes! Everyone, I'm Lacus Clyne!
まだまだ生誕祭、盛り上げていってくださいね！
Keep on livening up the birthday party!
静かな この夜に 貴方を待ってるの
In this quiet night, I am waiting for you
あのとき忘れた 微笑みを取りに来て
Come to take the smile that I forgot back then
あれから少しだけ 時間が過ぎて
Since then, just a little time has passed
想い出が優しくなったね
And memories have become gentle
星の降る場所で 貴方が笑っていることを
I was always wishing that you were smiling...
いつも願ってた
...in the place where stars fall
今 遠くても
Even if now you are far away...
また会えるよね
...we can meet again, right?
いつか微笑みは こんなに儚くて
One day, a smile became so fleeting...
ひとつの間違いで 壊れてしまうから
...because it can be broken by a single mistake.
大切なものだけを 光に変えて
Change only the precious things into light...
遠い空 越えて行く 強さだけ
...giving only the strength to cross the distant sky.
星の降る場所で
In the place where stars fall,
思いを あなたに 届けたい
I want to deliver my feelings to you.
いつも そばにいる
I'm always by your side.
We are in the quiet night
Dreaming in the night
歌うから 生誕祭が あるのでは ありません
It's not that there's a birthday party because I sing.
生誕祭が あるから 歌うので
It's because there's a birthday party that I sing.
星の降る場所で
In the place where stars fall,
あなたが 笑っていることを
I was always hoping...
いつも 願ってた
that you were smiling.
今 遠くても
Even if you're far away now,
また 会えるよね
we'll be able to meet again, right?
星の降る場所で
In the place where stars fall,
思いを あなたに 届けたい
I want to deliver my feelings to you.
いつも そばにいる
I'm always by your side.
We are in the quiet night
Dreaming in the night
いっぱい 聴いてくれて どうも ありがとう
Thank you so much for listening!
それでは 次は お待ちかねの ビデオレターです
Now, next is the long-awaited video letter.
どうぞ
Here it is.
周防パトラ お姉ちゃん
Big sister Suo Patra,
お誕生日 おめでとう ございます
Happy Birthday!
わーい パチパチパチ
Yay! *Clap clap clap*
VTuber カレン です
I'm VTuber Karen.
パトラ お姉ちゃん は 何度も カレン の 番組 に 出てくれたりして
Big sister Patra has appeared on my show many times,
カレン とっても とっても 感謝 しています
and Karen is very, very grateful.
最近 だと 去年 の 12月20日 の 生配信 かな
Most recently, was it the live stream on December 20th last year?
に ゲスト として 来てくれました
She came as a guest.
カレン それまで ちょっと コールドスリープ で お休み してたんで
I had been on a break in cold sleep until then,
まさか また ね パトラ お姉ちゃん が カレン の 番組 に 来て
so I never thought I'd be able to meet Big sister Patra again
再会 できる と 思ってなかった ので
on my show like that,
もう すっごく すっごく 嬉しかったんです
so I was really, really happy.
その時 は パピプペポゲーム で 盛り上がったり してましたけど
We had a lot of fun with the Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe-Po game then,
皆 見てくれた かな
I wonder if everyone saw it?
あ もし 見てくれてない 方 アーカイブ 残ってます
Oh, if you haven't seen it, the archive is still there.
はい そんな パトラ お姉ちゃん には カレン の ソロ曲
Yes, and for Big sister Patra, my solo song...
ラブメロディー も パトラ お姉ちゃん には 作って いただいて
Big sister Patra also created 'Love Melody' for me,
カレン ね いつか パトラ お姉ちゃん と 一緒に
and Karen's dream is to one day
その 曲 を なんだろう デュエット っていうのかな
sing that song together with Big sister Patra,
一緒に 歌えたら いいな っていう 夢 を 持っています
as a duet or something like that.
その 夢 が 叶う ように カレン も これから も 頑張りたい と 思います
I'll keep doing my best so that dream comes true.
パトラ お姉ちゃん も いつまで も 体 には 気をつけて 頑張ってください
Big sister Patra, please take care of yourself and keep it up.
では これから の 1年 も パトラ お姉ちゃん にとって
I hope the coming year is a wonderful,
素敵 な 素敵 な 1年 に なります ように
wonderful year for Big sister Patra.
パトラ お姉ちゃん 大好き
Big sister Patra, I love you!
おやすみなさい
Goodnight!
パトラちゃん お誕生日 おめでとう
Patra-chan, Happy Birthday!
漫画家 イラストレーター の 飯田ぽち。 と 申します
I'm manga artist and illustrator Iida Pochi.
この お仕事 を ね して おりますと
In this line of work,
時々 まあ 心身ともに エネルギー切れ に なって ね
sometimes I run out of energy both mentally and physically,
疲れ果てて しまう こと も 多い んですけれども
and I often end up exhausted.
そんな 時 に ね いつも パトラちゃん が
At those times, Patra-chan always says things like,
「新作 楽しみ に してます！」 読みました とか ね
"I'm looking forward to your new work!" or "I read it!"
「グッズ 買いました！」 とか 伝えて くださる ので
or "I bought your merch!"
いつも 私 ね 心 の 栄養 を もらって おります
so I'm always receiving nourishment for my heart.
パトラちゃん の おかげ で いつも 頑張れて おります
Thanks to Patra-chan, I can always keep going.
いつも ありがとう
Thank you always.
そんな ね パトラちゃん の 優しさ に 甘えて しまって いて
I've been leaning on Patra-chan's kindness,
わたくし 日頃 お世話 に なりっぱなし ですので
and I'm always in her debt,
そろそろ ね わたくし から も 何か 恩返し を させて ください ね
so I'd like to do something to repay her soon.
いつでも ね 何か あったら 気軽 に 声かけて ください
Feel free to reach out anytime if there's anything I can do.
という わけ で パトラちゃん の ますます の ご活躍 と
With that, I sincerely wish for Patra-chan's continued success,
そして 今年 が ね 素敵 な 1年 に なる こと 心から 願って おります
and for this year to be a wonderful one for her.
改めて 本日 は お誕生日 おめでとう ございます
Once again, Happy Birthday today.
飯田ぽち。 でした
This was Iida Pochi.
おめでとう
Congratulations!
パトちゃーん！ ハッピーバースデー！
Pato-chaaan! Happy Birthday!
お誕生日 おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
にじさんじ 所属
From Nijisanji,
夜見れなです！
I'm Yorumi Rena!
パトちゃんとはね、なんだかんだつるんで ASMR 絡みが多いですけど...
Pato-chan and I hang out a lot, mostly for ASMR-related stuff...
実は夜見、パトちゃんとゲームも一緒にしたいなーって思ってるんだよね。
But actually, I've been wanting to play games with you too!
なので今度一緒にゲームで遊んでください！
So please, let's play some games together next time!
またね、いつメンでご飯も行こうね。
And let's go out to eat with the usual group again.
もちろん、夜見と二人きりでもいいですけどね。
Of course, just the two of us would be fine too.
パトちゃんにとって素敵な一日を過ごしてね。
I hope you have a wonderful day, Pato-chan.
ほな、またね！
Well then, see you later!
連絡待ってまーす！
I'll be waiting to hear from you!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
パトラ、お誕生日おめでとう！
Patra, happy birthday!
最高の女がまた一秒一秒とこのように存在を刻んでいるね。
The greatest woman is carving her existence second by second like this.
このまま永遠に刻んでいってくれよな。
Please keep carving it like this forever.
突然私事なんですけれども、最近生活リズムが終わってるんですよね。
This is a personal matter, but lately my life rhythm has been a mess.
前々から始まったことじゃないんですけど、
It's not something that just started, but...
そこで私は、パトラの「おはよう配信」から始まって「ASMRおやすみ配信」で終わる、パトラ24が欲しいと思っているんです。
So, I want a 'Patra 24' that starts with your morning stream and ends with your ASMR sleep stream.
パトラ1日生活動画が欲しい！
I want a 'One Day in the Life of Patra' video!
パトラで俺の生活を整えたい！
I want to fix my life with Patra!
どうですか？
How about it?
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
パトちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Pato-chan, happy birthday!
いやー、誕生日ですか。めでたいですねー。
Man, it's your birthday. That's wonderful.
またね、プレゼント渡しに家行くからね. ぜひぜひ入れてください。
I'll come over to your place to give you a present later. Please let me in!
また行くからねー。お家だらだらしに行くからね。グッズも持って行くからねー。
I'll visit again to lounge around at your place. I'll bring some merch too.
おめでとう！またねー！
Congratulations! See you later!
ビデオレターありがとうございました！
Thank you for the video letters!
本当にね、いろんな子たちからのビデオレター、ありがたいです。家宝にします！ありがとうございました！
I'm really grateful for all the video letters from everyone. I'll treasure them! Thank you so much!
それではですね、次は告知になります！どうぞ！
Now then, next is an announcement! Here we go!
皆さん、こんにちわんわん！
Hello everyone, bow-wow-wow!
そう、パトラです。
Yes, it's me, Patra.
パトダイレクトをご覧いただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you for watching Patra Direct!
今日は全部で4つの告知があります。
I have four announcements to make today.
それではまず、こちらの告知をご覧ください！
First, please take a look at this announcement!
満たして　愛してみてよ
Fill me up, try to love me
悪い夢なら　壊してよ
If it's a bad dream, break it
この度、アミューズメント施設向けの音楽ゲーム、GITADORA シリーズのアリーナモデル筐体にて、楽曲収録することになりました！
This time, my music will be included in the GITADORA arcade series' Arena Model cabinets!
なんと曲は、メタル！
And the song is... Metal!
BEMANI Sound Team あさきさんとダブルギター！
It's a double guitar collaboration with BEMANI Sound Team's Asaki!
このライブが終わった後、ゲーム内で誰でもプレイできるようになります。
After this live stream ends, everyone will be able to play it in-game.
ゲーム内の GALAXY WAVE DELTA カテゴリーから選曲してみてね。
Look for it in the GALAXY WAVE DELTA category in-game.
初めて GITADORA をプレイするよという人は、ルーキーモードでぜひプレイしてみてください。
If it's your first time playing GITADORA, please try it out in Rookie Mode.
また、19時から KONAMI 公式 YouTube チャンネルからこの楽曲のフルバージョンもアップ予定。
Also, the full version of the song will be uploaded to KONAMI's official YouTube channel at 7 PM.
皆さん、ぜひ GITADORA で遊んでみてね！
Everyone, please go play it on GITADORA!
やったー！ついに発表！
Yay! Finally announced!
周防パトラフィギュア第2弾が登場しちゃいます！
The second Suou Patra figure is here!
今回のテーマは、ASMR配信の世界観を詰め込んだ、周防パトラ監修の完全オリジナルポーズ！
The theme this time is a completely original pose supervised by me, capturing the world of ASMR streams!
髪の毛は透明パーツで毛先まで美しく。
The hair uses transparent parts for beautiful tips.
お洋服の艶感、チョーカーやベルトの金具まで忠実に再現。
The texture of the clothes, and even the metal parts of the choker and belt, are faithfully recreated.
おへそ周りのシースルーは...はぁ...ため息もの！
The see-through area around the navel is... *sigh*... breathtaking!
お尻、胸、足裏まで、職人技で丁寧に仕上げました。
From the buttocks and chest to the soles of the feet, it's all carefully finished with craftsmanship.
耳かきやクッション、ラグマットも超可愛い！
The ear pick, cushion, and rug mat are also super cute!
クッションにはパトラのサイン入りだよ。
The cushion even has my signature on it.
そして、気分で楽しめる表情差し替えパーツ付き！
And it comes with interchangeable facial expression parts for different moods!
ちょっと困り顔も楽しんでね。
You can enjoy this slightly troubled expression too.
受注開始は 10/17 (金) から！予約受付中！
Orders start on Friday, October 17th! Now accepting pre-orders!
25日から開始です。
Starting from the 25th.
予約締め切りは10月17日までだよ。
The reservation deadline is October 17th.
絶対ゲットしてね！
Be sure to get yours!
はぁ〜 パトラちゃん、お腹が空いて力が出ないよ...
Haa... Patra-chan, I'm so hungry I have no energy...
そんな時はこれ！手作り風うみー！
In that case, try this! Homemade-style Yum!
パトラのカニカマカレー！
Patra's Kani Kama Curry!
ピリッとスパイスの効いたカレーに、
Spicy curry loaded with...
カニカマがゴロゴロ！うみー！
...chunks of crab sticks! Yum!
グラッシャス！ギリギリOKだね！
Gracias! Just barely made it, right!
ついに出た！周防パトラ全面監修。
It's finally here! Fully supervised by Suou Patra.
手作り風うみー！パトラのカニカマカレー！
Homemade-style Yum! Patra's Kani Kama Curry!
2025年10月1日発売！
On sale October 1, 2025!
一箱に二食入り。
Two servings per box.
パトラのオリジナルカードが全6種類、1枚入りだよ。
Includes one of six original cards.
そしてなんと！パトラのうめー皿＆
And what's more! Patra's "Umee" plate and...
パトラのうまいスプーンセット発売だよ。
...Patra's "Umai" spoon set are now on sale!
スプーンはパトラがイラストを描いたよ。
I drew the illustration for the spoon myself.
栄養満点！パトラの愛情も満点だよ！
Full of nutrition! Full of Patra's love too!
詳細はまたXなどでお知らせするね。
I'll announce the details on X and elsewhere.
楽しみにしててねー！
Look forward to it!
全部で3つの告知をご覧いただき、ありがとうございました。
Thank you for watching all three announcements.
ギタドラ、カレー、それからフリューさんでは
Gitadora, curry, and at FuRyu...
第2弾のフィギュアが出ることになりました！
...a second figure will be released!
楽しみですね。
I'm looking forward to it.
ついに、次は最後の告知です。ご覧ください！
And finally, here is the last announcement. Enjoy!
周防パトラ...？
Suou Patra...?
って、だれ？
...who is that?
記憶をなくしたパトラと、君が織りなす「もしも」の物語。
A "what-if" story woven by you and a memory-less Patra.
恋愛アドベンチャーゲーム『君色パトラIF』制作決定！
Romance Adventure Game "Kimiiro Patra IF" decided!
パトラのこと、拾ってくれますか？
Will you pick Patra up?
はーい！ということで、盛りだくさんの告知でした！
Haa-i! So, that was a whole lot of announcements!
みんなびっくりした？
Was everyone surprised?
あとでね、Xの方にも情報出しますので、よろしくお願いします！
I'll post info on X later, so please check it out!
そしてね、ここまでたくさん歌ったんですけど、次でラストの曲になります！
And, I've sung many songs, but the next is the last!
おー、コメントもたくさん、ありがとうございます！
Oh, thank you for all the comments!
じゃあね、今年もこうしてね、新3Dが出せたり、
Being able to reveal this new 3D and...
あの素敵なステージでライブができたのは、
...perform on this wonderful stage is...
応援してくれてるみんなのおかげです！
...all thanks to everyone's support!
今日もね、ハッシュタグでたくさん呟いてくれて、どうもありがとう！
Thanks for all the tweets using the hashtag today!
そしてそして、本日のステージを作ってくださいました、
And also, a huge thank you to Brave Group,
ブレイブグループの皆さん、本当にありがとうございました！
who created today's stage!
すごいんで、パトラがね、あの、パン、パン...あ、パンって言っちゃった。
It's amazing. Patra, um, pan, pan... oh, I said it.
あの、スカートの中ね、よく見せちゃうので、
I often show under my skirt, so...
今日、素敵なアングルを考えて撮ってくれました。本当にありがとうございました！
they thought about a nice angle for me. Thank you!
はい！それでは次の曲、なんと新曲になります！
Yes! Now for the next song... a brand new one!
ぜひ聞いてください！新曲は、『MINNA〜！』
Please listen to it! The new song is, "MINNA~!"
みっ、みっ、みっ、みんなーーーー！
Min, min, min, MINNAAAAA!
みんなは噛めば噛むほど味が出るもの知ってる？
Do you know what gets tastier the more you chew it?
人類の常識を超えて
Beyond common sense...
歴史を刻むもの教えてあげるね！
...I'll teach you something that carves into history!
(みんな！みんな！みんな！みんな！みんな！みんな！)
(Minna! Minna! Minna! Minna! Minna! Minna!)
ゲームするよー！
Let's play a game!
(みんな！みんな！み、み、み、みんな！みんな！みんな！)
(Minna! Minna! Mi, mi, mi, minna! Minna! Minna!)
高評価よろしくおねがい！
Don't forget to give it a high rating!
気が付いたら24時間ゲームばかりしてる
Before I knew it, I'd been playing for 24 hours straight.
現実？ 幻？ 夢の中？ どういうわけかやめられない
Reality? Illusion? In a dream? I just can't stop.
途中まで来てバグを引いて最初からやり直し
Caught a bug halfway and had to start all over.
爆笑 ガチ切れ それでもずっとやめられない
Laughing, getting mad... even so, I can never stop.
昔の昔の黒歴史 絶対誰でもあるよ (あるよー あるよー)
Everyone has a cringey past. They really do!
デバックちゃんとしたのかな？ なんて楽しんだもの勝ち 救え未来！
Did you debug it? The one having fun wins. Save the future!
あの一生懸命には意味がある！ パトはそう思います！
There's meaning in all that effort! Pat thinks so too!
みんな起きろ！ みんな叫べ！
Everyone wake up! Everyone shout!
バグがあってフリーズしたけれども...
There was a bug and it froze, but...
クソゲーなんて この世にない
There's no such thing as a trash game in this world.
クリアして笑ってやるのさ
I'll clear it and laugh.
みんな笑え
Everyone laugh!
みんな踊れ
Everyone dance!
きっと痛み我慢してるんだろう
You're probably enduring some pain, right?
ダサいのにね
Even though it's uncool,
うらやましい
it's enviable.
そんな風に生きてみたいだろ
You want to live like that, don't you?
気づいたらみんな みんな
Before you know it, everyone,
呼びかけたりしてる
is calling out to each other.
カミゲー ムリゲー クソゲー
God games, impossible games, trash games,
好奇心は止められない
curiosity can't be stopped!
良いことも悪いことも
Both the good things and the bad,
君の人生の味方になーれ
let them become allies in your life!
みんな起きろ
Everyone, wake up!
みんな叫べ
Everyone, shout!
ゲームオーバー またリトライすればいい
Game over? Just retry again!
あきらめられない ここで
I can't give up here,
ハッピーエンドに
for a happy ending!
みんな笑え
Everyone laugh!
みんな踊れ
Everyone dance!
勇気だけが武器じゃないように
So that courage isn't your only weapon.
あどけない服 走る心
Innocent clothes, a racing heart,
悲しいときには
when you're sad,
泣けばいいんだよ
it's okay to cry.
なーにをコソコソしてるんですか？
What are you whispering about?
もう 起こしてもいいかな？
Is it okay if I wake you up now?
いやいや 想いを込めたもの
No, no, everything I've put my feelings into,
すべてを見届けたい
I want to see it through to the end.
そんな行方が見たいだけ
I just want to see how it turns out.
みんなみんな不安なんだ
Everyone, everyone is anxious.
世の中にね 自分のこと
In this world, I wonder if there's someone
許してくれる人がいるのかな
who will forgive me for who I am.
挑戦したら勇者
If you try, you're a hero.
みんな起きろ
Everyone, wake up!
みんな叫べ
Everyone, shout!
涙があって 振り切ったけれども
Even though there were tears and I shook them off,
クソゲーなんて この世にない
there's no such thing as a trash game in this world.
クリアして見せて 笑ってやるんだ
I'll show you I can clear it and laugh!
はーい、お疲れ様でしたー！
Okay, thank you for your hard work!
ね、カニカマもいてくれたの？ どうもお疲れ様でした。
Oh, Kanikama was here too? Thanks for the help.
今日はね、あ、みんな！みんな！みんな！待ってたよー。
Today, oh everyone! Everyone! I was waiting for you!
今日はね、あの、なんと前回と同じステージと思いつつ、ちょっと変化があるんですよ。
Today, well, it looks like the same stage as last time, but there's a little change.
ステージの紹介をしたいなーって思います。まだまだあるよ。
I'd like to introduce the stage. There's more!
見て見て見て。これ、なんと前回よりもプレゼントが増えています。
Look, look! There are even more presents than last time.
どどーん。ほらほら、何が入っているのかなっていうね、形になってるのと。
Ta-da! See, they're set up like 'I wonder what's inside?'
あと、ここ！カニカマがちょっと変化してます。わかるでしょうか。
And here! Kanikama has changed a bit. Can you tell?
えー、間違い探しじゃないですけど、微妙に変わっております。
It's not exactly 'spot the difference,' but it's slightly changed.
なんと、カニカマが増えています！ 気づいた？気づいたかな？
Surprisingly, the number of Kanikama has increased! Did you notice?
あとステージ全体はこうなってます。おおー、豪華！
And the whole stage looks like this. Wow, so luxurious!
すごいよねー。キラキラ度も増しております。みんなも応援ありがとう。
It's amazing, isn't it? The sparkle level has also increased. Thanks for the support, everyone.
それからね、で、でっかいね、サムネイル。かわいい！
And then, there's the giant thumbnail. So cute!
同じ、同じポーズ。なんか違うような気がするけど、あ、同じポーズ。ね、すごい豪華に描いてもらいました。
The same pose! I feel like it's different, but oh, it's the same pose. It was drawn so beautifully.
それから、あーい！シロパトー！
And next, hello! Shiropato!
はいはいはい。ちょうどね、はい。あんまりね、出番がなかったシロパトちゃんです。
Yes, yes. This is Shiropato, who didn't get much screen time today.
ね、今日はね、1曲目歌ってくれてどうもありがとうね、シロパト。
Hey, Shiropato, thanks a lot for singing the first song with me today.
ね、みんなは白と黒、どっちのパトラが好き？
So, everyone, do you like the white or black Patra better?
おっ、あ、ね。シロパトちゃんのほうがちょっとね、柔らかいの。ほら、跳ねて跳ねて。
Oh, see? Shiropato is a bit softer. Look, she's bouncing!
そうなの。やっぱパトはね、あの鉄壁のベルトが巻いてあるからね。シロパトちゃんのほうが柔らかいんですよ。
That's right. After all, I have my 'ironclad' belt on. Shiropato is much softer.
ほらほら、よく見て見て. 二人のツーショット。みんな、どっちが好きかな？ どっちも好き？
Look closely! A two-shot of us. I wonder which one you like? Or both?
あ、ありがとうございます。あ、ぜひ高評価、チャンネル登録もぜひよろしくお願いいたします。
Ah, thank you. And please remember to like and subscribe!
みんな、本当に今日はありがとう。これからもよろしくね。バイバーイ！
Everyone, thank you so much for today. Please keep supporting me. Bye-bye!
生誕祭ライブ終わりました！
The birthday concert has ended!
つたない歌と豪華なステージではしゃぐパトが今年もできたのはあなたのおかげです。
It's thanks to you that Patra could have fun again this year with my clumsy singing and a grand stage.
今日もこの世界に生きててくれてありがとう！
Thank you for living in this world today too!
パトは今こうしていることが一番楽しいです。
Doing this right now is what I enjoy the most.
それはきっと世界で一番幸せなことです。　周防パトラ
That is surely the happiest thing in the world. - Suou Patra